RENATA REINARTZ CPA, FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

Calendly | Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

Calgary, AB T2J 6N5 | 8254374269 | renata.techie@gmail.com

WEB DEVELOPER SUMMARY

As a Frontend Web Developer, I develop accessible, responsive, and engaging websites and apps using WordPress, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, React, and JavaScript. As a former senior accountant and CPA, I have 10+ years of experience working in senior positions. I have a solid understanding of business processes, user needs, and leadership. My experience has equipped me with transferable skills including attention to detail, analytical skills, and problem-solving abilities. Besides coding, I've traveled extensively worldwide and received my yoga certification. I currently enjoy spending time with my family.

HIGHLIGHTED SKILLS

WordPress | HTML5 | CSS3 | SCSS | React | JavaScript | RESTful APIs | Firebase | Responsive Design| SEO | Google Analytics | Email Marketing Integration | Paired Programming & Team-Based Development | Version Control | Git & Github Web Accessibility | Project Scope Management | Time Management | Adaptability Detail Oriented | Problem Solver | Excel Pivot Tables | Khalix | Excel & VS Code Shortcut keys | ClickUp | Slack | Asana | Jasper | ConvertKit |

PROJECTS

Choose your makeup | HTML | SASS | React| GitHub | API | <LIVE> <REPO>

An elegantly designed and developed e-commerce website using React and the makeup API. The user can select the price and product they want. Includes a scroll to the top function.

Find your podcast | HTML | SASS | React | GitHub | API | <LIVE> <REPO>

A fun app where the user selects the length of their podcast using a slider and the genre of the podcast using the listennotesAPI. The user can also save to their playlist or delete their selection. Developed and designed collaboratively using peer programming techniques.

Who Is Your Animal Match? | HTML | CSS | SASS| JavaScript | GitHub | API | <LIVE> <REPO>

A lighthearted app that matches the user's personality to an animal photo. Using the user's inputs, it fetches data from the Pexels' API and displays the resulting match. Developed and designed collaboratively using peer programming techniques Fiona Freemark. Added Javascript including a scroll to the bottom on mobile and created a loader.

Bird of Paradise | HTML | CSS | SASS| JavaScript | <LIVE> <REPO>

• Are you a bird lover? This eye-catching landing page is for you. Developed this stunning birds-of-paradise landing page that is functional and responsive.

EDUCATION

Web Development Immersive Bootcamp, JavaScript, & Web Dev Juno College Of Technology	2023
WordPress Rockstar (incl Google Analytics) GeekPack	2022
Chartered Professional Accountant Chartered Professional Accountants Of Alberta	2015

Bachelor of Management | University of Lethbridge

WORK EXPERIENCE

Digital Marketing, Freelancer (Click TESTIMONIALS)

Sep 2021 - Present

Remote

- Design modern and pleasing WordPress websites using Elementor and Divi, leading to increased traffic between 20 - 40% for clients
- Installation of Google Analytics and SEO (Yoast plug-in, writing alt tags, meta descriptions, fixing broken links, and redirects) to improve SEO ranking and track client traffic
- Develop effective landing pages and pop-ups to increase engagement and subscription signups by 30%.
- Integrate email marketing systems, such as ConvertKit, set up tags, and create email automation and sequences for increased client conversion

RENATA REINARTZ FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

Calendly | Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

Calgary, AB T2J 6N5 | 8254374269 | renata.techie@gmail.com

Online English Teacher/Evaluator

Apr 2018 - Aug 2021

Whales English, Remote

- Promoted to an evaluator. Reviewed playback of over 40 teachers monthly (1000 + teachers in total) and wrote evaluation reports and suggestions for improvement which led to 30% higher client satisfaction and renewals
- Instructed ESL students in one-to-one and one-to-ten virtual settings using Zoom, with an established English curriculum, and tests that improved students' English speaking and writing abilities. Wrote weekly feedback and suggestions which led to higher marks and improved their fluency

Accounting Manager Mar 2014 - Dec 2017

Pacekids Programs, Calgary, AB

- Converted the company's software to QuickBooks Pro and implemented an accrual-based accounting system with monthly cutoffs which led to 98% more accurate reporting
- Created a monthly cash flow report and financial package for the board of directors which led to better spending practices and a more balanced budget
- Previously an accountant and promoted to accounting manager

Other Positions

Previous positions included Senior Financial Analyst, Accountant, and Corporate Reporting Analyst at multinational companies.

- Directed a team of five, providing mentorship and instruction
- Created billion-dollar monthly forecast reports using Khalix Longview, a financial reporting and performance management software integrated with Excel, and monthly reports for the CFO press conferences, ensuring accuracy and timeliness for quarterly and annual shareholder meetings